A Guide to the Marshall W. Fishwick Collection, c.1923-1935, 1940s-2006
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series I: Papers
  - Miscellaneous Popular Culture, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 20)
  - Bound to Rise, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 21)
  - Fear of Falling, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 22)
  - Hero, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 23)
  - Revivals, Gonzo, Madonna, etc., n.d. (Box 59, Folder 24)
  - Bond Revival, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 25)
  - Hero, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 26)
  - McLuhan, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 27)
  - Wonder Woman, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 28)
  - Visualization Charticle, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 29)
  - More McLuhan, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 30)
  - More McLuhan, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 31)
  - Ray, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 32)
  - Introduction, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 33)
  - Preface and Introduction, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 34)
  - Superman, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 35)
  - Conclusions - Afterthoughts, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 36)
  - Conclusion, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 37)
  - Battaglia, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 38)
  - Heroes/Celebrities, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 39)
  - Hero (popular), n.d. (Box 59, Folder 40)
  - Smithsonian, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 41)
  - Hero and Superman, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 42)
  - Old Files, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 43)
  - Bunyan, Paul, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 44)
  - Poky - Truth ?, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 45)
  - Barnes, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 46)
  - Glassie, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 47)
  - Faxes, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 48)
  - Photos WWII - Forward, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 49)
  - Law Notes, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Lexington Acct. Book, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Law Notes, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - History 180, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Yale, 1948-1949 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - History 180 and American Philosophy Notes, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Class Notes, 1947 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Yale Grad., n.d. (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - English 169, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - History W.H. AWG, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - National Diary, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Stamp Album, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Letters 1964 Volume II, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - James Graham Leyburn Library Scrapbook, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Fishwick Scrapbook 1 - Memoirs, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Memoirs and Personal Letters, 1990-1999 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Memoirs: Mid-Years, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Letters, Notes, etc, Revolt!, 1960-1969 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Change Scrapbook, 1959-1963 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Fishwick Scrapbook II, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Memoirs, 1990-1991 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Europe Scrapbook, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Family Memos, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Snow Flakes, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Buddha/Merton Mediation, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - John Henry, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Byrd, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - James Cabell, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Squires, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Golden Quill Press, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Writing Related to Cicero, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Writing Related to Cicero, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - The Study of a Culture - B.M. Forman, 1952 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Popular Culture Publications, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Ellie - Ted, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Sue and Jimbo, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Family Photos, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Photos, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Children, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - L.F.F., n.d. (Box 62, Folder 19)
  - More Photos, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 20)
  - Photo Album, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - 1950 - 1962, 1950-1962 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Hood/Cooperstown, 1960-1969 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Icons, Iconic Imagery, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Moss, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Barnes, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - de Battaglia, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Alex and Sin, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - 40 Years, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Brown/Mel, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Travel, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Family Photos, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - American Studies - Washington and Lee, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Leyburn, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Leyburn, J.G., n.d. (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Mudd, R., n.d. (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Wachman, M., n.d. (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Bill, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Poland and Kaya, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Junkin, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 21)
  - Grace Church, Lexington, Virginia, History, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 22)
  - Lexington and Lee, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 23)
  - Southwest, Virginia,> n.d. (Box 63, Folder 24)
  - Washington and Lee Reunion, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 25)
  - Lexington, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 26)
  - Lexington, Washington and Lee, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 27)
  - Villains, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 28)
  - Publishing, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 29)
  - Hero, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 30)
  - Popular Culture Ephemera, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 31)
  - Dreams, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 32)
  - Going to Europe, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 33)
  - Reviews, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 34)
  - Personal, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 35)
  - Celebrities, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 36)
  - More Cicero, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 37)
  - Hero ADD, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 38)
  - Two Agrarians, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 39)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 40)
  - American Hero Conclusion, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 41)
  - Re-Worded ADD, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 42)
  - Washington and Lee Flashcards, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 43)
  - Self-Made Men, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Robert Divinus, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Harper's and Dodd, Mead, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Bernstein, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Mudd, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Drake, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Grandpierre, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - United Kingdom: Griffiths/KAK, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Browne/Rollins, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Utopia, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Technology - Long View, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Internet, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Elec. Imperial, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Far Out - Notes, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Starving to Death in a Fat City, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - GAP!, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Information Highway - Frontier, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - Gates, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - Techno Faust Technopoly, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Computers - History, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Cyburbia, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 21)
  - Burg/Silvers, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 22)
  - Global Village, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 23)
  - Point of Purchase, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 24)
  - Factors, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 25)
  - Post Modern, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 26)
  - Tempo Hurry!, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 27)
  - Ray + Global, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 28)
  - Cyber Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 29)
  - Cyburbia Proposal, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 30)
  - Machines, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 31)
  - Essays - Rework, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 32)
  - Vita + Cyburbia, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 33)
  - Conclusion H. Adams, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 34)
  - McDonald, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 35)
  - My Travel Pieces, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 36)
  - Formulas/FADS, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 37)
  - Global Village, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 38)
  - Fishwick Books, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 39)
  - Hero, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 40)
  - Lucy Hallett: Introduction and Conclusion, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 41)
  - Chapter 1: Popular Culture and Heroes, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 43)
  - Footnote - H: Mar, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 44)
  - Rosa Parks, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 46)
  - New Cicero, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 47)
  - Reviews and Writings, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 48)
  - Celebrity Culture, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 49)
  - Indians, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 50)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 51)
  - Conclusion - Various, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 52)
  - American Heroes, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 53)
  - Lady - Publish, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 54)
  - Maps, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Fishwick Publications, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Maps, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Journals, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings and Photos, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Writings and Popular Culture, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - American Studies, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Essays, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Essays, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Willie Fishwick, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Family Photo - Framed, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Family Photo - Framed, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Family Photo - Framed, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Framed Photo, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Framed Photos, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Framed Photos, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Framed Photo, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Personal/Family, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Walden, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - 21st Century/Future, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Semiology, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Reprints Since 1986, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Descartes, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Falling Star, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Wolfe, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Hero, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Wolfe, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Forward, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Ice Age, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Wolfe, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Formula, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Plato -Cave, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Chronicles, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Owl, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Author - Contracts, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Thompson, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Mosiac Flyer, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Cars, 1995-1996 (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Cars, Tech, Comparin, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Car, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - Humanities 2504, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - The 60s, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - American Studies Various, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - American Studies, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Yale Reunion, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - Europe, Turkey, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 29)
  - Lincoln, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 30)
  - Images of Power, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 31)
  - Madonna, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 32)
  - Washington, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 33)
  - Prospects - Bello, Combs, etc., n.d. (Box 66, Folder 34)
  - Probing Overview, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 35)
  - Style Wars, Shopping, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 36)
  - Heroes, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 37)
  - Western Cowboys, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 38)
  - Cavaliers, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 39)
  - Civil War and Robert E. Lee, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 40)
  - Schroeder, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 41)
  - Lee, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 42)
  - Symbolism, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 43)
  - Salzburg, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 44)
  - Call for Book, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 45)
  - Cook, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 46)
  - Warhol, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 47)
  - Telephone, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 48)
  - Reprints, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 49)
  - Chaplin, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 50)
  - Myth, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 51)
  - Mosaic, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 52)
  - Celebrity Cowboy, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 53)
  - Bangladesh, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - India, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Sri Lanka, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Poland, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - A.S.R.C., n.d. (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Italy, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Italy, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Egypt, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Rome, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Fulbright, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - India, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Korea, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Denmark, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Bangladesh, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Bangladesh - Literary, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Indonesia, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Asia, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Asia, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Babu, India, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Russia, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - United Kingdom, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Hawaii, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Scotland, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 23)
  - Italy and Family Letters, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 24)
  - Asia and Information, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 25)
  - Virginia, 2001 (Box 67, Folder 26)
  - Horses, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 27)
  - Essays on Virginia, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 28)
  - Tourism, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 29)
  - Howell, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Virginia, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 31)
  - Southern Article Themes, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 32)
  - Lexington Remembered, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 33)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 34)
  - Vita, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Cicero, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Combs, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Literary, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Lady, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - War is Hell, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Haworth, 2003 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Haworth, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Bernstein, J., n.d. (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - American Studies, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Big Mac, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Barbara and Betty Saff, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - World War II, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Permissions - Galleys, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Sleepy - Muse, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - Popular War - CWII, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Cicero, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Distinguished, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Reprints, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 19)
  - New Photos, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 20)
  - Topics, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 21)
  - Culture and Introduction, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 22)
  - Popular, 2001 (Box 68, Folder 23)
  - American Dream, 2003 (Box 68, Folder 24)
  - Greenbrier, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 25)
  - Hamlet, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Mosaic, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 27)
  - Timet Style, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 28)
  - Folk/Fake/Pop-lore, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 29)
  - Help Wanted and Voyage into Unknown, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 30)
  - Art of Teaching, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 31)
  - F.A.R, 2000-2001 (Box 68, Folder 32)
  - "Disting" Papers, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 33)
  - F.A.R., 2002 (Box 68, Folder 34)
  - Where Are We Going, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 35)
  - C.I.S., n.d. (Box 68, Folder 36)
  - Student Letters, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 37)
  - Comm 3034, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 38)
  - 3034, 1994 (Box 68, Folder 39)
  - 4034 Spring, n.d. (Box 68, Folder 40)
  - American Literature Yale Notebook, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - American Literature Yale Notebook, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Literature Crit. College Notebook, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Law Notes, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Sociology Yale Notebook, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - International Popular Culture Journals, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - International Popular Culture Journal (Volume 1:2), n.d. (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Fishwick Publications, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Writings, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - The Commonwealth Magazine of Virginia, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Alumni Magazine: Washington and Lee, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Magazines and Journals, n.d. (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Saturday Reviews, 1952-1956 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Saturday Reviews, 1957-1958 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Saturday Reviews, 1961-1965 (Box 69, Folder 15)
- Series II: Audiovisual and Electronic Materials (Box 1-13, Box 70-71)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the audio and video materials in the collection, primarily resources used by Fishwick as teaching tools or in his research. This includes VHS tapes, audio cassette tapes, films, floppy disks, and an extensive set of slides. A spreadsheet of these materials by format is available for download and searching (file will automatically download).
  - VHS tapes (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5)
  - Film reels (Box 5)
  - Audiocassette tapes (Box 4, Box 5)
  - Computer disks (Box 4)
  - Floppy disks (Box 4)
  - Zip disk (Box 5)
  - Slides (Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 71)
  - Photograph album (Box 4)
  - Photographic negatives (Box 70)
  - Index cards (Box 4)
  - Wooden plank with key (Box 4)
- Series III: Oversize Materials
  - Map of Part of Virginia, 1929 (Folder 1)
  - Thomas Jefferson poster (Folder 1)